Caleb Filburn

Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania | (412) 626 1665 calebfilburn@gmail.com | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

UX and UI expert with 10+ years of experience in design and research, development, design systems, software engineering, and team leadership. Develops creative front-end solutions that optimize consistency and accessibility. Builds and empowers collaborative and dedicated teams, fostering transparency and accountability.

COMPETENCIES

Software Engineering: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, jQuery, Redux, Svelte, Jest, Node.js, .NET, C#, Razor, xUnit.net, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, REST, SOAP, Azure, Salesforce, Kentico, Sitecore, WordPress, HubSpot

Product Design: design systems, user research, usability testing, user flows, wireframes, mockups, interactive prototypes

UX Design Tools: Figma, Maze, Sketch, Miro, Balsamiq, Axure RP, Penpot

Graphic Design: branding, identity, photo, illustration, publication, typesetting, preflight, packaging, Adobe Creative Cloud

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, April 2022–August 2023

ISACA - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Remote)

Designed frontend components and maintained codebase and test suite for enterprise B2C software applications. Led meetings and presentations, mentored new hires, and reported project status to stakeholders.

- Designed and managed design system, resulting in 30% improved UI development efficiency
- Improved accessibility by adhering to WCAG 2 AAA guidelines
- Implemented software logging and fixes, reducing application errors by 80%
- Created onboarding process and documentation, resulting in estimated 50% reduction in training time for new hires
- Mentored new hires and led training on Kentico CMS and enterprise systems, enhancing team's capability and productivity
- Directed integration of FormAssembly with Sitecore and Salesforce via API, improving system data flow and communication

UX Engineer, October 2021-April 2022

ISACA - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Remote)

Co-led team responsible for company user experience. Created and maintained design system by owning and participating in all steps of UX design process.

- Built and deployed design system across multiple web applications resulting in 30% faster development time
- Conducted heuristic evaluations, usability testing, interviews, and feedback synthesis, leading to design improvements
- Designed, tested, and converted UI prototypes into functional components
- Performed rapid ideation, research, and presentations to drive informed design decisions and UX adoption

Software Engineer, March 2020–October 2021

ISACA - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Remote)

- Designed and developed new front-end features and unit tests for Sitecore sites
- Contributed to API development to optimize calls and add new functionality and integrations
- Integrated OneTrust, GA360, and Salesforce to replace legacy systems, streamlining data management and analytics
- Led adoption of Scrum by training new team, facilitating Scrum ceremonies, resulting in +24% development efficiency
- Managed project timelines and resources across teams

Frontend Developer, July 2018–March 2020

CMMI Institute - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

- Created and maintained design system, resulting in 25% faster development and greatly improving accessibility
- Established SLA for marketing and technology departments, reducing resolution time by ~50% and improving collaboration
- Conducted A/B testing, card sorting, and user interviews to inform design decisions
- Deployed Jira Service Desk and promoted its adoption, increasing collaboration and project delivery speed

Web Team Director, June 2016-July 2018

Em-Media - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

- Designed and developed websites and applications for clients in agency environment
- Provided DevOps for 30+ web projects, UX design, digital design, and ad placement
- Supervised team of 5 developers and content specialists
- Managed multiple simultaneous projects, adjusting priorities to stay on time and on budget

Web Designer, Partner, March 2013-June 2016

Chiselbox - Wheeling, West Virginia

- Co-founded successful boutique web and creative agency
- Guided new business development, business strategy, and financial decision, leading to ~100% yearly growth
- Managed accounts and provided creative direction in fast-paced startup environment while delivering high quality projects
- Created web components, identity systems, and branding assets for 20+ clients

EDUCATION

B.S., Graphic Design, 2013 West Liberty University

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master, Scrum.org
Design Systems and Pattern Libraries, Nielsen Norman Group
Certified CMMI Associate, CMMI Institute
Design Certification, HubSpot Academy
Marketing Certification, HubSpot Academy